





Summary

Jump to Section

Having 5+ years of experience specialized in Cloud Administration and Devops working on server-based operating system, and providing support in both Application and Production environment. Extensive experience in installation, configuration and administration of Redhat, CentOS 6/7. Troubleshooting System and Performance Issues under Client Server systems, along with systems integration and keen understanding of customer service and requirements. Seeking a growth oriented career in world of information and Cloud Technologies, Where I have more scope to learn advanced technologies and utilizing my skills in DevOps world.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Work Experience

- eClact infotech as DevOps Engineer Jul 2020 to Nov 2020
- Perform daily system monitoring, ensure the availability of the required storage spaces, verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, systems and key processes, reviewing system and application logs, and verifying completion of scheduled jobs such as backups.
- Involved in build and deployment Patch release, Full release, and Auto release activities using CI/CD Jenkins tool for any non-production environments.
- 3. Setup DEV, QA and UAT environments for every sprint using Ansible.
- 4. Created custom Docker images using Dockerfile.
- E&Y as DevOps Engineer Feb 2019 to Jun 2020

PROJECTS IN ANUTSHELL:

3) : e-Pragati -towards digital AP ∶ E & Y Project Name (#3)

Client

Role : Cloud Admin & DevOps

Team Size : 15

Tools : Pega, Zabbix, ELK, Jira, Tomcat, Rhel, Aws, Docker, K8s, Terraform Ansible.

Duration : FEB - 2019 to June-2020

DESCRIPTION

Concisely, 'my AP' Portal shall serve as first stop to discover all Government services / data and shall act as an information gateway to citizens & residents, government officials, businesses and non-residents. It shall also serve as a repository of e-Pragati's ONE GOVERNMENT Core Platform standards / guidelines, UX artifactory, Architecture references, DIY user guides and Developer Community.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Perform daily system monitoring, ensure the availability of the required storage spaces, verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, systems and key processes, reviewing system and application logs, and

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

verifying completion of scheduled jobs such as backups.

- 2. Involved in build and deployment Patch release, Full release, and Auto release activities using CI/CD Jenkins tool for any non-production environments.
- 3. Automated the building process and reduced all the manual intervention needed and merged that to the Jenkin's iob.
- 4. Setup DEV, QA and UAT environments for every sprint using Ansible.
- 5. Create and configure new jobs for each and every module in Jenkins.
- 6. Configuration of Jenkins CI tool for automated build and Integrating Jenkins with Docker.
- 7. writing playbooks to setting up complete application stack which includes services like Apache, Tomcat.
- 8. Launch EC2 instances, attach/detach ELB, create and restore backup of EC2 instances using AM.
- 9. Autoscale Groups, Launchconfig, Load balancer.
- Create IAM to manage aws console and various services for user and various application etc.
- 11. Implementation of alerts system using SNS, cloud metric and instance scale up/down triggers.

CGI as Cloud Admin (L1/L2) Oct 2015 to Feb 2019

PROJECTS IN A NUTSHELL:

Project Title(#1) : Core Banking System (C.B.S.)
Client : Union Bank of India (U.B.I.)
Role : Linux Administrator(L1)
Duration : OCT 2015 to JUL 2016

Team Size : 8

Environment : Rhel, Centos. Red Hat Sattelite.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- 1. F/S creation, modification & Logical Volume management (LVM)
- Setting up and administering NFS, NTP.
- 3. Sudoers users file management.
- 4. Patch management as per schedule
- 5. Linux operating environment installation.
- 6. System log collection and shared with backend team for H/W support.

PROJECTS IN A NUTSHELL:

Project Name (#2) : Release Management Office

Client : PARAGON CGI

Role : Linux Admin with Devops & Cloud

Team Size : 10

Tools : Rhel, Centos, Aws, Jira, Tomcat, Docker

Duration : July 2016 to FEB-2019

DESCRIPTION:

The Project Aims to build a Data warehouse solution for business people at their business, by integrating the business data from various source systems. Data mart is one of their major data warehousing applications that extracts data from various operational systems and loads into data warehouse. In order to analyze the whole seller amount and rate lock in different perspectives like retailer, customer, product rate lock, time, business unit and date, Merck implementing the data warehouse. It wanted the ability to make more timely business decisions regarding its loan pipeline in order to improve its business performance. Configuration of Jenkins CI tool for automated build and Integrating Jenkins with Docker & K8s with Azure cluster.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya (RGPV), Bhopal in 2012

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: RHCSA

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version | Last Used | Experience | |
|-------------------------------------|---------|-----------|----------------------|--|
| CentOS, Windows, Ubuntu, RHEL | | 2020 | 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| PostgreSQL,Oracle,MySQL | | 2019 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| Shell/Bash Scripting,Nagios, zabbix | | 2019 | 1 Year(s) 2 Month(s) | |
| Apache Tomcat | | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| LVM, NAS(NFS, EFS) | | 2019 | 2 Year(s) 5 Month(s) | |
| Crontab, AWS(Ec2,IAM),S3,VPC,Lambda | 1.15 | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| Ansible(playbook) GitHub,GIT | latest | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| DOCKER | latest | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| K8s | latest | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| Microsoft Azure | latest | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |

^ Back to Top

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English | Proficient | ✓ | ✓ | ✓ |
| Hindi | Expert | ✓ | ✓ | ✓ |

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: e-Pragati towards digital AP

Client: EY

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: VJAYWADA
Role: Network/System Administrator

Duration: Feb 2019 - Dec 2019
Onsite / Offsite: Onsite
Team Size: 12

Skill Used: Pega PRPCAnsibleJenkinsApache TomcatDockerAWS-CWIPostgresqlkubernetesGithub, Mcrosoft Azure Role Description: 1. Perform daily system monitoring, ensure the availability of the required storage spaces, verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, systems and key processes, reviewing system and application logs.

Project Details: Concisely, 'my AP' Portal shall serve as first stop to discover all Government services / data and shall act as an information gateway to citizens & residents, government officials, businesses and non-residents. It shall also serve as a repository of e-Pragati's ONE GOVERNMENT Core Platform standards / guidelines, UX artefactory, Architecture references, DIY user guides and Developer Community

Project Title: Release Management Office

Client: CGI Group

 Nature of Employment: Full Time
 Duration: Jul 2016 - Feb 2019

 Project Location: HYDERABAD
 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

 Role: Network/System Administrator
 Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Linux, Ubuntu, AWS, NAGIOS, SQL Server, Ansible, Github, Shell Scripting.

Role Description: Perform daily system monitoring, ensure the availability of the required storage spaces, verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, systems and key processes, reviewing system and application logs

Project Details: The Project Aims to build a Data warehouse solution for business people at their business, by integrating the business data from various source systems. Data mart is one of their major data warehousing applications that extracts data from various operational systems and loads into data warehouse. In order to analyze the whole seller amount and rate lock in different perspectives like retailer, customer, product rate lock, time, business unit and date, Merck implementing the data warehouse. It wanted the ability to make more timely business decisions regarding its loan pipeline in order to improve its business performance.

Project Title: core banking system UBI

Client: Union Bank Of India
Nature of Employment: Contractual
Project Location: HYDERABAD
Role: Network/System Administrator

Duration: Oct 2015 - Jul 2016 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Team Size: 10

Skill Used: Redhat Linux

Role Description: F/S creation, modification & Logical Volume management (LVM)

Setting up and administering NFS, NTP. Sudoers users file management. Patch management as per schedule. Linux operating environment installation.

System log collection .

Project Details: F/S creation, modification & Logical Volume management (LVM)

Setting up and administering NFS, NTP. Sudoers users file management. Patch management as per schedule. Linux operating environment installation.

System log collection and shared with backend team for H/W support.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: OBC - non-creamy Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.